<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="4.3.1">Jekyll</generator><link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="http://localhost:4000/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2024-06-03T19:19:27+02:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/feed.xml</id><entry><title type="html">Web Audio Conference</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2022/05/21/Web-Audio-Conference.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Web Audio Conference" /><published>2022-05-21T00:00:00+02:00</published><updated>2022-05-21T00:00:00+02:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2022/05/21/Web-Audio-Conference</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2022/05/21/Web-Audio-Conference.html"><![CDATA[<p>The <a href="https://webaudioconf.com/">Web Audio Conference</a> is an international conference that congregates the communitty 
interested in pushing further the web audio technologies and their applications. It gathers academic research, artistic 
research, development, design, evaluation and standards concerned with emerging audio-related web technologies such as
Web Audio API, Web RTC, WebSockets and Javascript.</p>

<p><img class="centerImage" src="/assets/images/wac21/WAC_2021_LOGO-02.png" width="200" alt="web audio confererence 2021 logo" /></p>

<p>It’s been celebrated 8 times since 2015 when it was born in Paris. In 2019 I had the honor of being selected to organise
the 6th edition in the Universitat Pompeu Fabra, Barcelona. Unfortunately, in 2020 the Corona Virus Pandemic hit and we
had to adapt the conference, to make it for the first time online (<a href="https://web.archive.org/web/20220327080440/https://webaudioconf2021.com/">web</a>).</p>

<p>Luckily, we had the sponsorship of <a href="https://www.gather.town/">Gather Town</a> where we created a virtual conference room 
where we held the conference. Poster sessions where great as we could walk around the Poster room to see every work exposed 
in each session.</p>

<p><img src="/assets/images/wac21/wac01.png" alt="web audio conferece 2021 conference room in gater town.com" /></p>

<p>We had the pleasure of having three great key note speakers.</p>

<p><strong>Anna Xambó</strong> specialised in human-computer interaction and music technology at Universitat Pompeu Fabra, 
and completed her PhD in music computing at The Open University. She gave a great talk her experiences and on network music performance.</p>

<div class="embed-container">
	<iframe src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/7SWu3txbg-w" width="700" height="480" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen="true">
	</iframe>
</div>

<!--https://github.com/nathancy/jekyll-embed-video-->

<p><strong>Juanjo Montiel</strong> is a senior software engineer and Microsoft Accessibility MVP. 
He gave us a master class on web accessibility and the great potential the web audio technolgies have to improve accessibility on the browser.</p>
<div class="embed-container">
	<iframe src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/sdlB-On6Rfk" width="700" height="480" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen="true">
	</iframe>
</div>

<!--https://github.com/nathancy/jekyll-embed-video-->

<p><strong>Anna Huang</strong> is a Research Scientist at Google Brain, working on the Magenta project. Her research focuses on designing
generative models and tools to make music more interactive and approachable. She holds a PhD in computer science from 
Harvard University and was a recipient of the NSF Graduate Research Fellowship.</p>

<div class="embed-container">
	<iframe src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/f0XO4A_-EeY" width="700" height="480" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen="true">
	</iframe>
</div>

<!--https://github.com/nathancy/jekyll-embed-video-->

<p>The event was a great success, and everyone in the community had a great time, thanks to our sponsors <a href="https://www.gather.town/">Gather Town</a>,
<a href="https://www./">Source Elements</a> and <a href="https://www./">Dolby.io</a> This event was also include as part of the 
<a href="https://www.sound2020.org/event/web-audio-conference-2020/">International Year of Sound 2020-2021</a></p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="Research" /><category term="Projects" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[The Web Audio Conference is an international conference that congregates the communitty interested in pushing further the web audio technologies and their applications. It gathers academic research, artistic research, development, design, evaluation and standards concerned with emerging audio-related web technologies such as Web Audio API, Web RTC, WebSockets and Javascript. It’s been celebrated 8 times since 2015 when it was born in Paris. In 2019 I had the honor of being selected to organise the 6th edition in the Universitat Pompeu Fabra, Barcelona. Unfortunately, in 2020 the Corona Virus Pandemic hit and we had to adapt the conference, to make it for the first time online (web). Luckily, we had the sponsorship of Gather Town where we created a virtual conference room where we held the conference. Poster sessions where great as we could walk around the Poster room to see every work exposed in each session. We had the pleasure of having three great key note speakers. Anna Xambó specialised in human-computer interaction and music technology at Universitat Pompeu Fabra, and completed her PhD in music computing at The Open University. She gave a great talk her experiences and on network music performance. Juanjo Montiel is a senior software engineer and Microsoft Accessibility MVP. He gave us a master class on web accessibility and the great potential the web audio technolgies have to improve accessibility on the browser. Anna Huang is a Research Scientist at Google Brain, working on the Magenta project. Her research focuses on designing generative models and tools to make music more interactive and approachable. She holds a PhD in computer science from Harvard University and was a recipient of the NSF Graduate Research Fellowship. The event was a great success, and everyone in the community had a great time, thanks to our sponsors Gather Town, Source Elements and Dolby.io This event was also include as part of the International Year of Sound 2020-2021]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Sonar+d 2020 Workshop</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2022/04/11/Sonar+D-2020-Workshop.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Sonar+d 2020 Workshop" /><published>2022-04-11T00:00:00+02:00</published><updated>2022-04-11T00:00:00+02:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2022/04/11/Sonar+D-2020-Workshop</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2022/04/11/Sonar+D-2020-Workshop.html"><![CDATA[<p>I had the opportunity to present a workshop in Sónar+D CCCB 2020 about how to use Essentia.js to
automatically detect quality problems in a music collection.
<!--more-->
Essentia.js is the port into web technologies of the C++ open-source library Essentia developed and
maintained by the Music Technology Group (MTG) of the Universitat Pompeu Fabra in Barcelona.</p>

<div class="embed-container">
	<iframe src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/NR9-hVLs4b8" width="700" height="480" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen="true">
	</iframe>
</div>

<!--https://github.com/nathancy/jekyll-embed-video-->

<p>In general, producers, djs, and audio engineers have to manually control if the audios they work
with have any issues. With this workshop, Sonosuite will show how the open-source Essentia library
can help detect automatically any problems that might exist in the audio tracks. They will also
learn how to control the final results of their work to adequately distribute it to all major
streaming platforms and digital shops.</p>

<div class="github-card" data-user="ljoglar" data-repo="workshop_sonar_2020_audio_problems"></div>
<script src="//cdn.jsdelivr.net/github-cards/latest/widget.js"></script>

<!--https://github.com/lepture/github-cards-->

<blockquote class="twitter-tweet"><p lang="en" dir="ltr">On the 18-19th Sep.<a href="https://twitter.com/luisjoglar?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">@luisjoglar</a> will be showing during the <a href="https://twitter.com/sonosuite?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">@sonosuite</a>&#39;s session at <a href="https://twitter.com/sonarplusd?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">@sonarplusd</a> how to automatically detect audio problems in your music collection using the <a href="https://twitter.com/Essentia_MTG?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">@Essentia_MTG</a> library &amp; web techs like Web Audio API and Canvas API. REGISTER NOW <a href="https://t.co/4QzS8GSYyf">https://t.co/4QzS8GSYyf</a> <a href="https://t.co/V4ye7zfTsY">pic.twitter.com/V4ye7zfTsY</a></p>&mdash; SonoSuite (@sonosuite) <a href="https://twitter.com/sonosuite/status/1306885357108187138?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">September 18, 2020</a></blockquote>
<script async="" src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="Coding" /><category term="Research" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[I had the opportunity to present a workshop in Sónar+D CCCB 2020 about how to use Essentia.js to automatically detect quality problems in a music collection.]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Apples</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2018/08/21/apples.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Apples" /><published>2018-08-21T00:00:00+02:00</published><updated>2018-08-21T00:00:00+02:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2018/08/21/apples</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2018/08/21/apples.html"><![CDATA[<p>An apple is a sweet, edible fruit produced by an apple tree.</p>

<p>Apple trees are cultivated worldwide, and are the most widely grown species in
the genus Malus. The tree originated in Central Asia, where its wild ancestor,
Malus sieversii, is still found today. Apples have been grown for thousands of
years in Asia and Europe, and were brought to North America by European
colonists.</p>]]></content><author><name>jill</name></author><summary type="html"><![CDATA[An apple is a sweet, edible fruit produced by an apple tree.]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Bananas</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2018/08/20/bananas.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Bananas" /><published>2018-08-20T00:00:00+02:00</published><updated>2018-08-20T00:00:00+02:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2018/08/20/bananas</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2018/08/20/bananas.html"><![CDATA[<p>A banana is an edible fruit – botanically a berry – produced by several kinds
of large herbaceous flowering plants in the genus Musa.</p>

<p>In some countries, bananas used for cooking may be called “plantains”,
distinguishing them from dessert bananas. The fruit is variable in size, color,
and firmness, but is usually elongated and curved, with soft flesh rich in
starch covered with a rind, which may be green, yellow, red, purple, or brown
when ripe.</p>]]></content><author><name>jill</name></author><summary type="html"><![CDATA[A banana is an edible fruit – botanically a berry – produced by several kinds of large herbaceous flowering plants in the genus Musa.]]></summary></entry></feed>